All boarders, please come out to the pier!
ご乗船の方は 桟橋へどうぞ
Hey, you're in the way! Move it!
ほら 邪魔だ 退け
Sorry, I'm not here to see you off.
見送りじゃなくて 悪かったなぁ
We both have jobs to do, huh?
お互い仕事だろう
Lawless Heaven?
Lawless Heavenか?
Yeah.
You'd make a fortune selling that in Chicago!
こいつはシカゴで売りゃ ぼろ儲けだなぁ
コルテはいい奴だった
Corteo was a nice guy. Fango probably fed him a line or something...
きっとファンゴの野郎に騙されたんだ
But we still gotta finish it.
だが ケジメはつけなきゃならねぇ
Hey!
May I go?
行ってもいいか
Yeah.
It looks good on you.
なかなか似合ってるね
kanjou ni tsukeru
I can assign whatever name I wish
namae wa jiyuu dane
To these emotions.
hora kawarihateta
See, they've already ceased to change.
kesenai boku no
The trigger of
tsumi no hikigane ga
My unrepentable sins
toketeshimaisou de
Seems ready to melt away,
nikushimi ga kieteshimattara
But if this hatefulness fades,
kimi o korosenai kara
I'll lose my chance to kill you.
kako o tannou shiteiru
I'm experiencing every moment of my past,
tsumi ga tsukutta boku ni kawaru tame ni
Trying to become the person who created these sins
ASL no naifu de
With an ASL knife.
kioku no signal kizamareteru noni
Despite the signal carved into my memories,
itami sae keshisatteshimau kizuna no spiral
Even the pain is erased away by this spiral of causality.
Having wandered in, I begin to fade... ceasing to be myself.
mayoikonda boku wa boku de kietekureteiku
Proof of Good Faith
誠實的證據
Corteo didn't show?
コルテオは現れなかったか
Yeah, Avilio set off for Chicago alone.
うん アヴィリオは一人でシカゴに向かったぜ
He's not in on it. How many times do I have to tell you?
彼奴は無関係だ 何度言ったら分かる
It was you, wasn't it?
あんただったんだなぁ
Right answer, Angelo.
正解だ アンジェロ
Why did you send me that letter?
何故俺に手紙をよこした
Vincent kept worrying over Testa's son that got away.
ヴィンセントは逃げたテスタの息子を気に病んでいてな
He told me to track you down by any means necessary.
どんな手を使ってでも お前を探しだすよう頼まれた
Don't worry.
安心しろ
You're dead, as far as he knows.
お前はもう死んた事になってる
To be honest, my hopes
weren't high, but you did well.
正直 大して期待してなかったが上出来だ
少しヘマしたみたいだが
You made a few blunders along the way, but the way you killed Vanno had style.
バンノンの殺しっぷりもいかしてたぜ
Why do you want the Vanettis dead?
あんたは何故バネッチィの奴らを
Good liquor, good women,
旨い酒にいい女
and the town of Lawless, all for me.
それにローレスの町 すべてを手に入れる
It's any man's fantasy.
男のロマンだ
You killed Nero, right?
ネロはやったんだろうなぁ
I can kill Nero any time,
ネロはいつでもやれる
but Vincent won't go down that easily.
でも ヴィンセントはそうは行かない
To kill Vincent, I need you.
ヴィンセントを殺すためには あんたが必要だ
You need me as well, right?
あんたも俺が必要なんだろう
Let me have Corteo.
コルテオを渡してくれ
Once he's safe, I'll come back.
逃がしたら戻ってくる
And if I refuse?
嫌だっと言ったら
I've entrusted the letter to a certain man.
手紙をある男に預けた
It gets sent to Nero if I die.
俺が死ねば ネロのもとに届く
With the name of the man who really sent it.
本当の差し出し人の名前を添えてなぁ
For now, you should pick a familiar place to lay low.
とりあえず 落ち着く先は馴染みの場所がいいだろう
They have the best prices there!
あの店やすいんだい
Oh, really?
あら そうなの
Mr. Bruno! Where have you been?
ブルノさん どこに行ってたんだい
Hey, you owe me back rent!
ちょっと 家賃溜まってるよ
Excuse me, will this cover it?
あの これで
This is too much!
これじゃ多すぎるよ
Take it as an advance on future rent, too.
この先の分も ここから取ってください
What?
There's so much...
こんなに...
It's quite spartan, isn't it?
随分質素だね
Yeah.
I'll sleep here for tonight.
今日は僕がここに寝るよ
These are...
これは...
この部屋に居た時
When I lived in this room I was an empty shell.
俺は抜け殻だった
Until that letter came...
あの手紙が届くまでは
Morning.
おはよう
Hey.
You slept well.
よく寝ってだなぁ
I hadn't been sleeping much lately.
ここんところ あまり寝てなかったから
Want some?
飲むだろう
This is the only cup I have.
カップ これしかないんだ
So sweet...
甘っ
You always did love sweet stuff, didn't you?
昔から 甘いものが好きだったよね
I need to go shopping.
買い物に行かなきゃ
What do you need?
何を買うんだ
Blankets, utensils...
毛布とか 食器とか
後 せっかく来たんだから
Oh, and as long as I'm here, why not
take me to some of your favorite places?
お気に入りの場所とかも連れてってよ
Yes.
ええ
Give my regards to Mr. Strega.
ストレーガさんによろしく
Corteo...
コルテオ
You're going back to Lawless, right?
ローレスに戻るんだろう
Yeah, I'll stop by Chicago, then head back.
あぁ シカゴに寄って そのまま戻る
You'll come back here, won't you?
帰ってくるよね ここに
Yeah.
I'll be back.
帰ってくる
Avilio!
アヴィリオ
How's the playhouse coming?
劇場の方は
Right on schedule.
順調だ
The orchestra we've got rehearsing
is saying good things about it, too.
リハーサルに入ってる楽団からも評判がいい
I see.
そっか
It's been a long road,
色々あったが
but if we can patch up our
relationship with the Galassias,
ガラッシアとの関係がしっかりすれば
that should clear up the last of our worries.
とりあえず憂いはなくなる
Yeah, if you can't beat 'em, join 'em.
あぁ 長いものには巻かれろってやつだ
What they want is to expand steadily,
奴らが望んでいるのは着実な発展だ
not to destroy and conquer.
破壊と征服じゃない
礼を尽くして付き合う限り
As long as we're courteous, they'll be reasonable.
無茶はしないだろう
Won't let us live, but won't kill us...
生かさず殺さず
その上で 俺達から上前を撥ねて
They'll just hang over us at all times, taking kickbacks and growing fat.
ブクブク太っていく訳だ
I understand how you feel,
お前の気持ちも分かる
だがな ガラッシアその気になれば
but in as little as a month, if they wanted to they could...
ほんの一ヶ月で...
Don't worry.
安心しろよ
I'm not so stupid as to try something right away.
今すぐどうこうしようって程バカじゃね
Think carefully, then walk forward with purpose.
よく考えろ そしてゆっくりと歩め
The faster you rush, the more likely you are to trip and fall.
速く走ろうとする者ほど 転びやすいものだ
Right?
だろう
Dad...
オヤジ
No matter what happens, I'll protect the family.
俺は何があっても ファミリーを守り通して見せる
Jeez, we can't find that guy anywhere.
ったく どこ探しても見つかんねぜ
コルテオもそうだが
I'm concerned about Corteo... but about Avilio, too.
アヴィリオが気になる
He called us from Chicago, remember?
でも シカゴから連絡があったんだろう
He said the deal went great.
取引は上手くいったって
The Galassias corroborated, too.
ガラッシアからの裏も取れてる
He's been gone a week.
やつがここを発ってから一週間だ
If he'd gone straight to Chicago, it'd have only taken a day.
まっすく向かえばシカゴまで 丸一日あれば行ける
Come on, it's his big trip to Chicago.
おいおい せっかくシカゴに行ったんだ
What's wrong with spending a few days living the high life?
二三日遊んだって別に悪くねだろう
The women they've got there ain't like the ones here.
女だって こっちのと浮気が違うだろうしよ
That's right.
そりゃそうだ
昔シカゴの女を抱いた時は
The woman I took to bed in Chicago
left me limp for a week. Sickly, even.
一週間骨抜きされて病気まで
What are we talking about?
なんの相談だ
Avilio!
アヴィリオ
Hey, want a drink?
や なんか飲むか
Sounds like business went well.
商売は上手くいったようだな
Yeah, we got almost everything we wanted.
あぁ こっちの言い分は大体通った
It took you quite a while.
随分遅かったな
There was a lot in Chicago that I had to try out.
シカゴじゃ 色々試さなきゃならなかったからな
See? What'd I tell you?
ほらな
So, how was it?
で どうだったんだよ
They got good stuff over there?
向こうの上物は
Nothing much.
大したことないな
The quality of the alcohol was poor.
アルコールの質も低い
カクテルにして誤魔化すならとまかく
They can mix it in cocktails to hide it, but the straight stuff is crap.
そのままじゃ話にならない
Huh?! You were talking about booze?!
酒の話かよ?
There's no booze in Chicago
that can top Lawless Heaven.
ローレスヘブンに勝る酒はシカゴにはない
Don Galassia and his underboss, Strega, both agreed.
ドン ガラッシアとアンダーボスのストレーガも認めていた
Honest to a fault, are they?
バカ正直な野郎だぞ
Anyway, let's have a toast.
とりあえず 一杯やろうぜい
Avilio, tell us some stories from your trip.
アヴィリオ 土産話でも聞かせてくれ
Sure.
I'm glad you came back.
よく戻ってきたな
You had me worried.
ひやひやしたぞ
本字幕由✿花語&千夏字幕組✿共同製作
このままコルテオと仲良く逃避行でもされたら
I was afraid you might run off with
Corteo, and then where would I be?
どうしようかと思ってな
My revenge isn't finished yet.
復讐はまだ終わってない
I'm relieved to hear that.
その言葉が聞けて安心した
The playhouse's big opening is in three days.
劇場のこけら落としは三日後だ
Vincent will be leaving his
mansion for the first time in a while.
久しぶりにヴィンセントが屋敷を出る
You'd better keep him safe.
しっかり守るんだぞ
What's wrong?
どうした
Nothing.
いや
Avilio.
アヴィリオ
Use it well.
大事に使え
Can't believe it's just two days away.
いよいよ明後日か
Don Galassia will come, as promised.
予定通りドンガラッシアも来る
That means he officially
accepts the Vanettis as friends.
ヴァネッティを正式に身内と認めたってことだ
Nero, this town is yours!
ネロ この町はお前のもんだ
Not yet.
まだ早い
There are still those with lingering loyalty to Fango.
ファンゴの残党は未練たらたらだ
There's also Corteo...
そして コルテオ
お前とヴィンセントは
You and Vincent will need the best security you can get to protect the guests.
万全の態勢でゲストを警護しなきゃならん
Just leave all that to me.
その辺の手配は任せておけ
Sure.
Where's Barbero?
バルベロはどうした
He said he was meeting someone at the pier.
なんか 波止場で人と会うとか
That man...
その男
Did he look like this?
こんなだった
Dunno. Can't seem to remember.
さーな 思い出せね
Can you come now?
今から来れるか
We've got a lead about Corteo.
コルテオのことで動きがあった
Yeah.
Sorry, but I need to search you.
悪いけど 調べさせてもらうぜ
You found out where Corteo's hiding?
コルテオの居場所が分かったのか
Nope.
いいえ
You let Corteo escape, didn't you?
お前がコルテオを逃がしたか?
お前がシカゴに経った日
The day you left for Chicago, Corteo was at the pier.
コルテオは波止場にいた
Isn't that true?
そうだな
Answer me, Avilio!
答えよ アヴィリオ
Someone there saw Corteo.
コルテオを見たものがいるんだ
What?
なんだ
Well...
それが
Save it for later!
後にしろう
Hey, wait! Hey!
ちょっと待て おい
Pardon.
ちょっと
Are you a friend of Mr. Bruno's?
あんた ブルーノさんの友達かい?
You'd better stay away from him.
あの子には近づかないほうがいいよ
Why?
なぜ
"Why?"
なぜって
He doesn't have a proper job, yet he has all that money...
真面に働いてもないのに お金持ってて
Listen, take my advice.
悪いことは言わないからさあ
Just stay away from him!
付き合うのはおよしよ
I...
僕は...
I'm his brother.
僕はあいつの兄弟なんです
R-Really? Well, I do beg your pardon.
そ そうかい そりゃ悪いこと言ったね
Forever.
ずっと
No matter what happens.
何があっても
This is your favorite place?
ここがお気に入りの場所なの?
Yeah.
You came here a lot?
よく来てたの?
No. It's my first time.
いや 初めてだ
That day, Luce told me
あの日 ルーチェが言ってた
he wanted to go to the zoo someday.
動物園に行ってみたいって
We can start over.
僕たちはやり直せる
We'll start over together.
二人で生き直すんだ
Mr. Corteo?
コルテオさん
You have a call from a man named Angelo Lagusa!
アンジェロ ラグーザって人から電話だよ
Avilio!
アヴィリ
Corteo.
コルテオ
Come back at once.
すぐに帰ってこい
You need to save Avilio.
アヴィリオを救ってやってくれ
You sit here.
ここに座れ
Why did you try to kill Nero?
なぜネロを狙った
I don't recall doing anything to earn your hatred.
俺はお前に恨まれるようなことをした覚えはねえ
Why?
なぜだ
I wanted to save Avilio from this ridiculous place.
僕はアヴィリオを救い出したかった こんなくだらないところから
With you gone...
お前さえいなければ
Damn you...
てめえ
Were you and Avilio working together?
お前とアヴィリオはグルだろ
No. I did it all of my own initiative.
違う 全部僕が勝手にやったことだ
It was Avilio who got you out of the garage, too?
ガレージからお前を逃がしたのもアヴィリオだ
No.
違う
お前を波止場で見た者がいる
Someone saw you on the pier the day Avilio left for Chicago.
アヴィリオはシカゴへ発ったその日に
I've never been there.
そんなところ行ったこともない
Liar! You both went after Nero together!
嘘をつくな お前たちは二人でネロを狙っていた
Avilio's in your way, isn't he?
あんたはアヴィリオが邪魔なんだろ
He could steal your position as Nero's right hand.
ネロの右腕の座を奪われるのが
Enough.
もういい
But, Nero...
しかしネロ
These two have always been...
こいつらは昔からの...
You kill him.
お前がやれ
Why did you come back?
なぜ 戻ってきた
Ganzo said that you were in danger...
ガンゾから君が危ないって
But even if he hadn't, it would end the same way.
でも 連絡がなかったとしても同じことさぁ
Either way, I'd end up...
どの道 僕は...
You can use that gun to clear their suspicion of you.
その銃で アヴィリオの疑いも晴れる
No one will get in your way after that.
もう誰も 邪魔する奴はいない
I am here to take revenge.
復讐するためにここにいる
It's not done yet.
それは終わってない
It's been a crazy ride, hasn't it?
なんだか 慌しかったなあ
アヴィリオがこの町に戻ってきてから
Has it really only been three months since you came back to this town?
たった三ヶ月か
But I'm glad I got to see you again.
でも また会えて嬉しかった
Why?
なんて
Why did you come back?
なんで 戻ってきたんだ
Angelo... Because we're...
アンジェロ だって僕たち...
Because we're brothers, right?
だって俺たち 兄弟だもんだ
I'll see you soon.
すぐに会えるさぁ